# Leonardo Boulitreau

#### Al Audio Research Engineer

■ leonardoboulitreau@gmail.com | 😭 leonardoboulitreau.github.io | 🛅 leonardoboulitreau

# About Me

I am a researcher in the intersection of artificial intelligence and speech, with over 4 years of experience and a solid background in signal processing. Currently, I work as an AI Audio Researcher @CPqD. My research efforts are directed towards developing human-machine interaction systems that are more affective and human-empowering.

# **Skills**

**Deep Learning** PyTorch, Tensorflow, HuggingFace, ONNX, Gradio, MLFlow **Speech Frameworks** Coqui, SpeechBrain, Amphion, ESPNET, NeMo, Kaldi

**Tools** Docker, Git, Kubernetes

Cloud AWS, GCP

**Programming** Python, C, C++, MATLAB, LaTeX **Languages** Portuguese, English, French

**Competences** Paper Implementation, Experiment Design, Team Collaboration

# **Experience**

#### Junior AI+Speech Researcher

São Paulo, Bra

@CPQD - RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS 🕋

2023 - Present

- Improved the company's emotion recognition system in production, in terms of speed and performance, by developing a 2-step self-supervised based neural emotion recognition architecture.
- Enriched the company's call center customer profiling product by developing and sending to production age and gender classifier models.
- Currently upgrading the company's automatic speech recognition (ASR) system with external large language model fusion techniques.

Fellow Master São Paulo, Brazi

@CPQD - RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS

2021 - 2023

- · Developed neural customer-oriented expressive text-to-speech models for the Brazilian Portuguese language.
- Enabled customers to customize the synthesized audios' prosody in a fine-grained way by implementing character-level prosody control graph
  pipelines.
- · Designed and conducted several subjective perceptual experiments to evaluate synthetic audio quality and naturalness.

Laboratory Intern Paraíba, Brazi

@ LPS - PROTOTYPING AND SIMULATION LABORATORY

2020 - 2021

- Enhanced lab automation by designing neural speech commands recognition systems.
- Encapsulated the ASR system in a local private LoRa network for IoT purposes.
- · Enabled long distance voice control by developing a wearable prototype with an embedded microphone.

### **Education**

## M.Sc. in Computer Engineering

@UNICAMP (STATE UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS)

São Paulo, Brazi

2021 - 2024

• GPA: 5/5

- · Thesis: Cross-Speaker Style Transfer for TTS based on Singing Voice Conversion Data Augmentation, Style Filtering, and F0 Matching
- Study On The Cross Modality of Pre-Training: Can models pre-trained in different domains adapt to a different one on a downstream task? 🧿
- Study Meta-learning strategies to build a few-shot emotion classifier. 🖸

#### **Exchange Student (Excellence Scholarship)**

Paris France

2019 - 2020

Studying Machine Learning, Statistics, Optimization, Digital Signal Processing, IoT and Telecommunications.

#### **B.Sc. in Electronic Engineering**

araíba, Brazil

2015 - 2021

@UFPB (State University of Paraíba) 🕋

• GPA: 8.38/10

@TÉLÉCOM PARIS

- Research Wind velocity estimation via the Extended Kalman Filter (DSP).
- Participated in the Electronics team of the national Aerodesign competition.
- Differential and Integral Calculus Tutor.